The Lorawan protocol
like all protocols get new features from time to time.
Since its first release in 2015, there has been a few updates,
so new versions.
The Lorawan protocol is managed by an alliance called the Lora Alliance.
They started with version 1.0, which has been updated into five new specifications for 1.0.0 to 1.0.4
on the last 1.0.4 was released in October 2020.
So you can go on the Lora Alliance website and download the details of the specification because that's where
they are available.
In 2017, there has been an evolution of the Lorawan protocol from the 1.0 to 1.1.
Even though it would new features, this version hasn't been adopted by the industry and only Lorawan
network servers are compatible with it.
So the new 1.2 version is now under way, but there won't be major changes from 1.1.
So in this course we will only focus on all 1.0 versions.
But don't worry about the new specification.
It would be an easy step to integrate 1.1 and 1.2 features.
Once you're comfortable with 1.0 protocol. However, there is an important thing to know when you're
up to deploy a Lorawan infrastructure.
The device protocol version must be supported by the networks server.
That is, it won't be possible to connect a 1.1 device with a network server only dealing with 1.0.1
end devices.
However, the nice thing is that all 1.1 network server support all 1.0 end devices.
Finally, one less thing each time a lorawan specification is released.
There is a companion document called the Lorawan regional parameters and it goes to the details of
the frequency band you're using. In this course,
so far we've mainly spoken about the European 868 MHz band.
Anyway, if you have any doubt about one detail of the Lorawan protocol, it's always a good idea to have a look
at the specification and regional parameters.
You should find all the information you need.
But of course, we're here to help you.